Guide to the Eliasaf Robinson Tel Aviv Collection M1522
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series IV. Noncommercial institutions
  - Subseries F. Government of Palestine and government of Israel
    - Correspondence and other documents. Three stamps, "Palestine Revenue 10 Mils," undated, in English, Hebrew, and Arabic. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - File folder cover: "Medinat Yisrael: misrade ha-memshalah: mekorot ha-mayim le-Tel Aviv" (State of Israel: Offices of the government: Water sources for Tel Aviv) (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Contents of the file, mainly memoranda and handwritten notes (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Subseries G. Jewish Agency
    - Employment verification of employees for visa purposes, mainly from business owners in Tel Aviv to the immigration department (mahleket ha-aliyah) of the Jewish Agency in Jerusalem (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Employment verification of employees for visa purposes, mainly from business owners in Tel Aviv to the immigration department (mahleket ha-aliyah) of the Jewish Agency in Jerusalem (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Visa requests sent to the immigration department on behalf of individuals by employers and relatives. Includes mailgram sent from the Warsaw ghetto, written on March 23, 1942, from Tejga Frank to Benjamin Goldstein in Haifa. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Subseries H. Legal documents
    - Miscellaneous legal documents (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Subseries I. Medical documents
    - Miscellaneous medical documents (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Subseries J. Miscellaneous correspondence, etc.
    - Includes photocopies of two postcards written in 1949 from new American immigrants to Israel (originals filed under postcards), etc. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Subseries K. Political activity
    - Pamplets, flyers, etc. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Small handbills (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Posters (Map-folder 17)
    - Posters (Map-folder 22)
    - Handbills, etc. (Flat-box 22, Folder 6)
- Series V. Photographs
  - Subseries A. Albums, loose pages, mounted prints, glass slides
    - Three mounted prints, "Tel Aviv," "The river Yarkon near Tel Aviv," and "Street in Tel Aviv," by S. Narinsky. Note on back: Sheet-fed gravure 1921 Handcrafted 1980. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Three mounted prints, "Tel Aviv," "The river Yarkon near Tel Aviv," and "Street in Tel Aviv," by S. Narinsky. Note on back: Sheet-fed gravure 1921 Handcrafted 1980. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Two identical albums of photographs of Tel Aviv and environs. Adhesive stamp on lower pastedown, The Bedouin Album S107 Johnsons London, no date, ca. 1930s (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Halvaa Vehisachon, Jaffa-Tel Aviv Cooperative Society Ltd., souvenir album of photographs in honor of twentieth anniversary, 1918/19-1938/39 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Loose pages of photographs from albums (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Loose pages of photographs from albums (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Framed photograph, "Makelot ha-mosad le-hafatsat musikah ba’am senif Tel-Aviv, 1.7.1929". (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Cover and pages from handmade photo album, "Tel Aviv mishe-kevar: albom temunot", includes black & white and tinted postcards, ca.1920s and 1930s (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Large format photographs, misc. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - 4 glass slides, Tel Aviv street scenes, no date (Box 24)
  - Subseries B. Buildings, etc.
    - Photographs of Tel Aviv buildings, ca.1920s-1960s, no date (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of Tel Aviv buildings, ca.1920s-1960s, no date (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of buildings and street scenes, ca. 1920s-1960s, no date (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of buildings and street scenes, ca. 1920s-1960s, no date (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Photographs of buildings and street scenes, ca. 1920s-1960s, no date (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Subseries C. Commercial
    - Photographs taken for commercial purposes, ca.1920s-1960s, no date (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Subseries D. People and events
    - Photographs, ca.1920s to 1960s, no date (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Photographs, ca.1920s to 1960s, no date (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Photographs, ca.1920s to 1960s, no date (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Subseries E. Postcards
    - Pre-1948 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Pre-1948 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Pre-1948 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Post-1948 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Post-1948 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Shanah tovah greetings (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Souvenir sets, pre-1948 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Souvenir sets, pre-1948 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Souvenir sets, post-1948 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Souvenir sets, post-1948 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Tinted, ca.1920s, circa 1920s (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Subseries F. Published photographs
    - Photographs removed from books and periodicals (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Photographs removed from books and periodicals (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Series VI. Tel Aviv Municipality
  - Subseries A. Administrative documents
    - Administrative, misc. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Administrative, misc. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B. Ephemera
    - Includes "Speech delivered by M. Dizengoff Ezq., O.B.E., Mayor of Tel-Aviv, Chairman of Levant Fair Committee at the Opening Ceremony, April 26th 1934" (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Municipal publications, including "Memorandum of Evidence Submitted by the Mayor of Tel-Aviv to the Anglo-American Committee of Enquiry," March 1946 and "Master Plan for Tel-Aviv-Yafo," 1954 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Municipal publications (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Municipal publications (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Municipal publications (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Municipal publications (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Posters printed by the Tel Aviv Municipality (Map-folder 15)
    - Posters printed by the Tel Aviv Municipality (Map-folder 16)
  - Subseries C. Civil Guard (Mishmar ezhrahi) and military
    - "Ha-behalah ve-emtsae ha-hitgonenut bi-fanehah" by Professor Popenheim (notes from a lecture on combating panic), 5.7.42 (July 5th, 1942); and cloth armband with civil guard insignia (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Subseries D. Memorabilia
    - Pennants, 1950s and 1960s; booklet marking 50th anniversary of Tel Aviv; Souvenir Leaf with stamps honoring 80th anniversary of Tel Aviv, 1989 (2) (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Educational materials for children relating to Tel Aviv’s 75th anniversary, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Memorabilia: framed cloth flag with municipal shield in center and lettering that reads "Yovel Tel-Aviv (1929-1934)." (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Memorablia: olive wood penholder, four medallions, small olive wood medallion holder (Flat-box 17)
    - Memorabilia: assorted metal pins and buttons (Flat-box 18)
  - Subseries E. Letters: incoming
    - Miscellaneous correspondence addressed to the Tel Aviv municipality (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Subseries F. Letters: outgoing
    - Miscellaneous outgoing letters (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Subseries G. Hawker licensing
    - Correspondence and other documents relating to licensing of street vendors, 1920s-1930s (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Subseries H. Meeting minutes
    - Meeting minutes, 1930s-1940s (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Subseries I. Sewer Department
    - Correspondence addressed to the Sewer Department (Folder 19, Folder 5)
    - Tel Aviv and Region: Sewerage and Sewage Disposal: Contract No. 1: Tel Aviv Interim Measures: Contract Drawings., undated; Bound serwer diagrams; G. B. Kershaw & Kaufman. Contract Engineers. Westminster and Tel Aviv. (Map-folder 20)
      City planning -- Israel -- Tel Aviv.; Jaffa (Tel Aviv, Israel) -- History -- 20th century.
    - Tel Aviv and Region: Sewerage and Sewage Disposal: Exhibition Drawings Illustrating Developed Proposals. G.B. Kershaw & Kaufman Consulting Engineers, Westminster and Tel Aviv. Bound sewer diagrams, no date (Map-folder 21)
    - Town Centre Interim Sewerage Scheme, 1940 (Flat-box 21)
  - Subseries J. Street census
    - Bound notebook containing Tel Aviv street names with partial lists of residents of those streets, no date, ca.1928-1934 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Subseries K. Technical Department
    - Certification requests: Letters from individuals detailing their qualifications and requesting certification from the Technical Department in order to work for the city as engineers or architects (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Certification requests: Letters from individuals detailing their qualifications and requesting certification from the Technical Department in order to work for the city as engineers or architects (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Certification requests: Letters from individuals detailing their qualifications and requesting certification from the Technical Department in order to work for the city as engineers or architects (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Certification requests: Letters from individuals detailing their qualifications and requesting certification from the Technical Department in order to work for the city as engineers or architects (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Diplomas (included with requests for certification as proof of technical education) (Flat-box 23)
    - Din ve-heshbon li-shenat 1937-1938 shel mah’ "mapat ha-rikuz" (Report for 1937-1938 of the department of the concentration map); file containing summary by head municipal engineer Y. Shifman, maps, and population data (Flat-box 22)
    - Personnel file: Eliezer Aronov, engineer employed by the city, 1940-1941 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Personnel file: Michael Gjebin, engineer employed by the city, including notice of his death while serving in the British Army in 1943, 1934-1943 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Street paving contracts, 1944 (2) (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Subseries L. Transportation
    - Correspondence, tickets, and other items pertaining to bus, taxi, and sea transportation (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Series VII. Clippings, etc.
  - Newspaper and other serial clippings and supplements relating to Tel Aviv (Flat-box 21)
- Series VIII. Addenda
  - Subseries A. Accessions 2009-016, -017, -089, -090
    - I: D Commercial: Chelouche Family documents, 1940s. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - I:E Commercial: Construction & Housing: Shikun ovdim prospectus. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - II:C Culture: Misc. Lup 03: Magazin rehov ivri be-tel aviv, 1994. Pamphlet: Bet Ben Gurion, ca. 1990s. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - II:C Culture: Misc. 2 calendars: Tel Aviv-Yafo 100th Anniversary, Turnowsky 2008/9; Israel Then and Now, Matan Arts Publishers Ltd. 2008/9. (Flat-box 30)
    - II:J Culture: Sport: Betar Tel Aviv medallion. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - III:A Maps: Tel Aviv: Neveh Tsedek, 2007; Taarukhat ha-asor, ca. 1960s. (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - IV:A Associations: Letter: Vaad ha-bitahon shel shekhunat ha-tikvah u-sevivoteha, 9.4.48., 1948 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - IV:A Assocations: Bayit shitufi bet shel Ha-peles: documents, 1943. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - IV:A Associations: Mikhtav hozer shel histadrut refuit ivrit be-e"i. No date., Circa 1920s (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - IV:A Associations: Kofer Ha-yeshuv. 2 letters, 1939. (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - IV:D Noncommercial: Education: Title page with inscription from "Kinus hanikhe mahzor yud bet g.i.h," 1934. (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - IV:K Political activity: Handbills. (Box 28, Folder 10, Flat-box 30)
    - IV:K Political Activity: Poster: Behirot ha-poel ha-mizrahi. No date, ca. 1940s. (Map-folder 15)
    - IV:K Political Activity: Poster: Behirot ha-histadrut. No date, ca. 1940s. (Map-folder 15)
    - IV:K Political Activity: Poster: Berit ha-tsohar, 1935. (Map-folder 15)
    - V:A Photographs: Pages removed from album (military scenes around Tel Aviv, 1947) (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - V:B Photographs: 6 photographs from the studio Yanovski et Berman. (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - V:D Photographs: 3 by Ben Rothenberg, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - V:E Postcards: 3 b&w, n.d., ca. 1930s; set of 7 b&w, n.d., ca. 1950s; 5 color, n.d., ca 1960s. (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - VI:K Tel Aviv Municipality: Technical Department. (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - VI:K Tel Aviv Municipality: Technical Department. (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - VI:K Tel Aviv Municipality: Technical Department. (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - VI:K Tel Aviv Municipality: Technical Department. (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - VI:K Tel Aviv Municipality: Technical Department. (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - VI:K Tel Aviv Municipality: Technical Department. (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - VI:K Tel Aviv Municipality: Technical Department. (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - VI:K Tel Aviv Municipality: Technical Department. (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - VI:K Tel Aviv Municipality: Technical Department. (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - VI:K Tel Aviv Municipality: Technical Department. (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - VI:K Tel Aviv Municipality: Technical Department. (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - VI:K Tel Aviv Municipality: Technical Department. (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - VI:K Tel Aviv Municipality: Technical Department. (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - VI:L Tel Aviv Municipality: Transportation pamphlet. (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - VI:L Tel Aviv Municipality: Sikumim: Seker bohan shel motsa ve-yi`ud be-Tel-Aviv. May, 1960. 13 p. (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - Hesder ha-tenu`ah: bi-tekufat beniyat ha-ma`avarim ha-tat-karka`iyim le-holkhe regel be-Khikar Magen David. 1960 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - VI:M Tel Aviv Municipality: Construction Department. (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Subseries B. Accessions 2009-225, -226, -259
    - IV:K Political activity: poster. Vaadat ha-behirot la-moetsah ha-shishit shel iriyat Tel Aviv. Tel Aviv, December 10, 1935. (Map-folder 16)
    - IV:K Political activity: handbill. Iriyat Tel Aviv: Buletin le-matsav beriyuto shel rosh ha-iriyah mar m. dizengof., September 19, 1936 (Flat-box 30)
    - IV:K Political activity: Handbills. Death notice for Meir Dizengoff. 1936 (Flat-box 30)
    - IV:K Political activity. Hodaah mis' 8 (announcement 8). Status reports by the Tel Aviv municipality on violent clashes and deaths around the country., August 27, 1928 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - IV:K Political activity. Hodaah mis' 10 (announcement 10). Status reports by the Tel Aviv municipality on violent clashes and deaths around the country., August 28, 1929 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - IV:K Political activity. Hodaah mis' 11 (announcement 11). Status reports by the Tel Aviv municipality on violent clashes and deaths around the country., August 29, 1929 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - IV:K Political activity. Hodaah mis' 15 (announcement 15). Status reports by the Tel Aviv municipality on violent clashes and deaths around the country., September 1, 1929 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Subseries C. Accessions 2010-012 and 2010-024
    - Ha-'Ir: Musaf tsilumim miyuhad. Keshe-rakevet hatstah et alenbi. [Newspaper supplement featuring photographs of Rudi Weissenstein.], April 11, 29 Nisan 5762 [2002] (Flat-box 30)
    - Souvenir cowrie shell, 9 x 4 cm., with "Tel Aviv" engraved on top. No date, ca. 1940s. (Box 29)
    - Set of 8 postcards enclosed in card stock folder: Bauhaus in Tel Aviv. Tel Aviv: Sabinsky Press, 2000. (Box 29)
    - "Hitnahalut" agudah shitufit be-am [Cooperative Society Ltd.], Tel Aviv. Account booklet and membership application, n.d., ca. 1940s (Box 29)
    - Handbill: Tel Aviv Municipality: Instructions on what to do when encountering the city's first traffic light. (Box 29)
    - Hand-drawn map showing current and future sewer lines in Tel Aviv., 7.8.1941 (August 7, 1941) (Box 29)
    - Ticket to a youth concert of Hebrew music. Words by the poet Hayim Nahman Biyalik; music by the composer Gavriel Grad., 23.6.38 (June 23, 1938) (Box 29)
    - Ha-ti'ul veha-biyuv be-tel-aviv [Drainage and sewerage in Tel-Aviv], by Y. Shifman. 55 p., Sept/Oct 1933 (Box 29)
    - Metalworkers' union newsletter: Electricians' and pipefitters' edition., May, 1938 (Box 29)
  - Subseries D. Accession 2010-133
    - Sefer ha-kupah shekhunat Brener. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Notes in connection with the proposed scheme for the sewering of the mercaz-mischari (commercial-centre) Tel Aviv., Circa 1930s (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Revised notes by the municipal engineer on the main drainage scheme in Tel Aviv: House connections., 20.1.1939 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Jaffa sewerage. J.D. and D.M. Watson, Westminster., April, 1937 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Water usage graph, Tel Aviv Municipality. Ha-shimush be-mayim le-fi hodshe ha-shanah, 1931-1935. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Small poster publicizing "Hagigat hakhnasat sefer torah..." Histadrut ha-mizrahi and His' ha-poel ha-mizrahi, 21.2.38., Feb. 21, 1938 (Folder 22)
    - Three-color poster, Habimah, matinee schedule for Dec. 11-15, 1947.
  - Subseries E. Accession 2012-151
    - Letter from Meir Dizengoff to Shimon Rokah, June 15, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Election pamphlet, Moetset iriyat Tel-Aviv-Yafo, June 27, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Goldberg letter on Gimnasyah Ivrit Hertsliyah stationary., December 12, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Takanot ha-agudah "am oved" (vaad la-milhamah be-sifrut)., July 10, 1936 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Handwritten census letter and notebook., July 13, 1938 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - First day cover for stamp, Meir Dizengoff, the First Mayor of Tel Aviv, November 5, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Two tickets to Chopin piano competition, n.d., circa 1950s (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Tell-Aviv (sic) Boy-Scouts postcard., circa 1920s (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Tel Aviv Municipality notices for civil defense; charitable donation stamps (n.d ca. 1950s); and prompt payment of taxes (March, 1957). (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Movie handbill, "Ahavah ve-retsah," kolnoa Hatikvah, Tel Aviv., March 23, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - 3 postcard sets & 14 b&w and color postcards of Tel Aviv, circa 1920s-1960s (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Muzeon Yafo pamphlet, 1959; Tel Aviv-Yafo Tourist Map, 1974; pamphlet: Guided tours of Tel Aviv-Yafo, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Subseries F. 2014 accessions
    - 14 photos of Tel Aviv. Tel Aviv Port -- Levant Fair -- Cafes, 1930s-1940s (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - 23 postcards of Jaffa, 1910s-1930s (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Paper bag. Le-zekher hanahat even-ha-yesod la-Gimnasyah ha-'Ivrit be-Yafo [In honor of the laying of the cornerstone of The Hebrew Gymnasium in Jaffa] 10 Av 5669 [28 July 1909] (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Scenes of Tel Aviv, 21 postcards, one greeting card, 1950-1975 (Box 33, Folder 4)